<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shirzart Enwer</title>
    <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shirzartenwer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shirzart Enwer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 11:52:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/images/icon_hudaf2fd83df7c62683b8b46f3900481ab_15352_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Shirzart Enwer</title>
      <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginners guide to startup research</title>
      <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/beginners-guide-to-startup-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 11:52:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/beginners-guide-to-startup-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Innovation is one of the most exciting elements that drives the progress of humanity. While many forms of innovations take place on different scales, startups are one of the key driver for innovative technologies to have a real impact on our daily life. However, not every startup will make it to be a standing enterprise that brings innovation on regular basis. Thus, being able to spot the right startups, the one that really makes impact on the long term is a treasurable skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to obtain these skills. Yet, I am still on my way to have a diamond-spotting eye. However, I did accumulate some experiences in 2-3 startup market research projects that I did. This is a introductory guide for people who want to get their hand on the market research fast and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pick-your-sward-for-the-fight-great-search-engines-for-startup-data&#34;&gt;Pick your sward for the fight: great search engines for startup data.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good warriors looking for the victory on the battle field, will never be shy on polishing their weapons.  While startup market is very early staged and doesn’t have a nice consistent data quality and no plat form has all the data about the startups around the world. &lt;strong&gt;It makes a good search engine stand out even more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the three platform, that’s friendly to  individual users, with nice trial free trial option for you to rocket your search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crunchbase-powerful-query-builder-and-nice-design&#34;&gt;Crunchbase: powerful query builder and nice design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crunchbase has been a very established platform in the field. It&amp;rsquo;s also easily the go to option if you are looking for a platform that is friendly to free plan users.
&lt;img src=&#34;crunchbase.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cruchbase interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive and accurate data bases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most powerful query tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice UX experience. Easy to navigate to different information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive pro plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bonus
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friendly refund policy for accidental extension of pro plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had several times ran into the problem of forgetting to cancel my subscription plan for crunchbase. Then I got a bill of approx 780 dollars on my credit card each time. However, the great thing about crunchbase is, &lt;strong&gt;as long as you file an refund request within 1 week of paying the subscription fee&lt;/strong&gt;, you will be able to get your money back. And you don&amp;rsquo;t really have to write a very pity email to ask them. Their customer service staff is really awesome. The official link for this policy is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.crunchbase.com/terms-of-service/cancellation-policy/#:~:text=For%20example%2C%20if%20you%20signed,charges%20associated%20with%20your%20subscription&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealroom-collection-of-similar-companies&#34;&gt;Dealroom: collection of similar companies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dealroom is a newly emerged startup from Europe that is specifically targeting the field of company research. They have caught some attentions by winning some awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dealroom.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dealroom interface&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice and clean UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good data quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No clear of the cost of pro plan yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Con:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smaller databases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cbinsight-great-cluster-analysis-and-summary&#34;&gt;CBinsight: Great cluster analysis and summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBinsight is well-known for their research output. I&amp;rsquo;ve been subscribed to CBinsights&#39; newsletter. From time to time, they will show you a very well down cluster graph that is almost all-inclusive in the targeting area.
For example, the following graphs summarized startup that worth paying attention
to in the digital health market.
&lt;img src=&#34;feature.png&#34; alt=&#34;CBinsight cluster&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pro
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great cluster analysis graph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great research insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Con:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short trial period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relatively bad UI experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-powerful-auxiliary-gartner-report-on-startup-hype&#34;&gt;A powerful auxiliary: Gartner report on startup hype&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great tool to have overall insights of certain industry from time perspective.  The before mentioned search engine only gives you a static data point in time. Gartner reports actually put the development of technology in development perspective. It’s a great tool to detect the potential of a certain company is as big as they promised on their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, graph like this that is showing the different stages of technology development in a particular field, gives you the time perspective when you are new in a certain technology market.
&lt;img src=&#34;Gartner_graph.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gartner_graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are my 5 cents in useful market research tools. Hope this will be helpful for any beginners to tackle market research problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life with purpose </title>
      <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/a-life-with-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 21:11:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/a-life-with-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not sure from where or who did I first hear about Victor Frankl and his book &amp;ldquo;Man&amp;rsquo;s search for meaning.&amp;rdquo; But it always have been a book that I wanted to read. Surviving one of the most serious disaster in human history, his book presented detailed his physical and mental suffer in several concentration Nazi&amp;rsquo;s concentration camps. With his surviving off the camp, he proves that in whatever condition a mankind face, even the worst possible one, there is still encoded freedom and dignity in human nature. However dim a man&amp;rsquo;s life can be, there is always a meaning to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankl was an established psychiatrist by the beginning of 1940. Parallel to the Freud and Adler, Victor is the representative of the third school of psychiatry theory: Logotherapy. He showed his talent in a young age and studied with both Freud and Adler, he didn&amp;rsquo;t agree with either school of psychology. He firmly believed that human life is not centered by the pursuit of happiness nor the pursuit of superiority. Instead, the central thesis of human&amp;rsquo;s life is a meaning. With some years of practice, he further developed the theory and started to write a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before he was taken in to Auschwitz in 1940, he was already established and running a clinic in Vienna, which still took Jewish people. When Nazis suddenly appeared at his door and took him to the camp, he had the manuscript of the book with him. Little did he know, the only asset he could preserve in the camp is his bare body. Yet it is still the luckiest case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./Victor_portrait.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through of the worst condition one could imagine and survived with sheer luck, in this book, Frankl breaks down the three phases of mental struggle that a typical prisoner goes through. Everyone who wasn&amp;rsquo;t sent to the gas chamber still faced a tough mental challenge with extreme weather and physical conditions to preserve mental sanity. &lt;strong&gt;Once the belief of survival is gone, disease will soon conquer the very weak body and take away once&amp;rsquo;s life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in this extreme condition, Frankl proved his theory by holding up to the belief that &lt;strong&gt;all these suffering will have a meaning and his life has a meaning.&lt;/strong&gt;
With this strong belief, not only did he survived concentration camps, he also lived a long life until 92 years old. When was taken to the camp, he was 35. Five years would passed when he survived and it also took away his wife, brother, and both parents. He would never made it out and had an impactful life until 92, if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t hold on to the strong purpose &lt;strong&gt;he chose for himself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing him overcoming all the psychological challenges gives the reader a sense of confirm and encouragement, to boldly pursue one&amp;rsquo;s purpose without any hesitations. As one of my favorite excerpt from the book says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live as if you were living for the second time and had acted as wrongly the first time as you are about to act now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beauty of Design Thinking</title>
      <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/the-beauty-of-design-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 21:58:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/blog/the-beauty-of-design-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you like wondering about big ideas from now and then, but don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be useful someday? Well most of us might had a day or two where you think about another way of going to school, taking classes, commuting in the cities or just having a different memory system or anything,  like the kind of future scenario that none of the science fiction wrote about it, yet its so intriguing. The joy of indulging myself in the wonderland of imagination is always so liberating. Yet most of these things never make a stop further than being forgotten at the back of your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I also enjoy building things from scratch. Unlike the most geeky kids who started out with computer programming at early age, my earliest building projects were all kinds of Mini models that compose a great toy after being built. There was a time when a Japanese Anime about miniature 4WD was viral in Urumqi. I spent numerous evenings of my primary school days to build them. The joy of composing something that&amp;rsquo;s working was unparalleled. I would easily spent 2 hours without thinking about anything else to try to finish the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./Mini4WD_model.jpg&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was not very easy most of the time to combine those joys together. The joy of thinking wildly and the joy of making something happen. The mismatch between the magnificat scale of envision and the limited power of implementation without technology was the limiting factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if, there is something that make the gap between imagination and implementation so small that it won&amp;rsquo;t even stop you from doing it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you might what to know design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-both-wild-ideas--fast-implementation--iterative-improvement--design-thinking&#34;&gt;Have both: Wild ideas + Fast implementation + Iterative improvement = Design Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design Thinking literally means the thinking process used by designers when they create a new concept. It is a perfect tool to utilize your big ideas and generate innovative solutions. It&amp;rsquo;s maybe not the first framework to encourage fast implementation, nor wild ideas, nor iterative improvement. But the combination of these elements makes it an organic process for the solution and the problem to co-evolve, while delivering the solution that user never realized wanted. It&amp;rsquo;s like delivering a car when the client says &amp;ldquo;I just want a faster horse.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./Henry-Ford-Faster-Horse-600x282.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the three elements: wild ideas, fast implementation, and iterative improvement interplay in the process, it&amp;rsquo;s not forseeable which ideas you will have and what implementation is it. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to know what element of technology you want to add, however, before implemented, no one knows what will come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does design thinking actually work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blank-canvas-to-brilliant-ideas-be-open-test-your-assumption-be-flexible&#34;&gt;Blank canvas to brilliant ideas: be open, test your assumption, be flexible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to have a successful design thinking session is to always be open to new ideas and be suspicious about the assumptions you make about the user. All these key elements are wrapped in an interactive session that is very well described by 2 diamond. Though there are different ways to represent the design thinking process, we developed this concept of 2 diamonds during InCube project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./2_diamonds.png&#34; width=&#34;860&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the whole design thinking process breaks down into problem space and solution space, each spaces are made of a diverging process where you &lt;strong&gt;brainstrom ideas and be open-minded&lt;/strong&gt; and a converging process where you &lt;strong&gt;examine your assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; by using testing method such as rapid prototyping, etc. The key in the converging face is to be flexible and not fix your mind on an existing solutions. Moreover, the quality of diverging phase also set a tone of how innovative your solutions can be. The more open-minded you are, the more surprise you will find in the end.There are lot of techniques go into the process of testing and validating assumptions, which will not be discussed in detail here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the design thinking process is never a one time project. The whole process could be repeated iteratively for as many times as you need when time is not a problem. The real joy I find in the process is when I can be as wild as I want in brainstorming, while being as rigorous as I can achieve in testing the assumptions and developing solutions. There is intellectual joy hidden in the making of a great idea or MVP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is why I ❤️ Design Thinking :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Semester Project</title>
      <link>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/project/my-semester-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:23:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shirzartenwer.github.io/project/my-semester-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-information&#34;&gt;Background information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global warming is a well-sound alarm occupying the news everyday, before the corona hit us. The most relatable source of pollution or contribution for an average joe might be the black smoke coming out of the chimney from nearby power plant. Indeed, coal-fired power plant is one of the main contributor to emission of green house gases, but what is little know to many people is, it&amp;rsquo;s not only green house gases being emitted by power plant. Sometimes it also contains heavy metal pollutants,for example, mercury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But from all the emission happened from global power plants, how much mercury emission happened every year? After they are emitted, how would they distribute globally? While, if it&amp;rsquo;s really bad, what can we do to reduce it? How well the effect of reduction be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been some studies investigating in this question, but it&amp;rsquo;s still rather new. My thesis project was then focusing on answering those questions by 1) modelling the mercury emission 2) Calculating the mercury gaseous concentration distribution globally, 3) Purpose the mitigation strategy and model the effect after the mitigation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-given&#34;&gt;What is given?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting the work, I used an existing model, developed by the lab that I worked for, to calculate global mercury emission. Another model which is co-developed in the lab for calculating gaseous mercury concentration distribution is used to calculate the global mercury concentration distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model the mercury emission scenario.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An emission calculation model was developed by Ecosystem Design Lab. I use this to calculate global mercury emission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparison by visualization&lt;/strong&gt; : I needed to reproduce a similar visualization in R and compare it to original visualization, without knowing what program or how the visualization was generated in the reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose mitigation strategy to reduce mercury pollution:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propose strategy on a global scale to reduce global mercury emission and concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare the result by visualization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study the effect of mitigation strategy on a local scale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;result-of-the-study&#34;&gt;Result of the study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compare the produced visualisation with reference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present the global and local change with the same visualisation scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss the pro and cons of visual comparison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-compare-the-reproduced-visualization-of-data-and-graph&#34;&gt;1. Compare the reproduced visualization of data and graph&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plot from reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/AMAP_2050_dataset.JPG&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plot from me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/AirTGM_adapted_2010.png&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original plot is probabaly generated in MATLAB. I used R to best mimic the visualisation to help me compare
how good is our computation method, compared to the reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the general color representation, it could be seen that my visualisation was very close to the original one.
Keep in mind that the computation method is also different. So it will result in actual different value in some cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;21--global-change-of-mercury-concentration-after-mitigation&#34;&gt;2.1  Global change of mercury concentration after mitigation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/AMAP_2050_dataset.JPG&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graphs shows what would mercury concentration in the air be if the emission we have is like in year 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/AMAP_2060_emission.png&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph shows, the scenario where some technologies are adapted to reduce the emission in 2010 and what would the mercury concentration in the air be in 2060.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;distribution-of-global-power-plants&#34;&gt;Distribution of global power plants&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/Powerplants_distribution_woSO2vsALL.png&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;22-global-mercury-concentration-change-after-upgrading&#34;&gt;2.2 Global mercury concentration change after upgrading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce the mercury emission and resulting concentration in the air, two different methods are purposed to apply technology upgrade to a selection of power plants. The following graph display the results of this technology upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both graphs display the percentage decrease of mercury concentration in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of using A technology
&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/1st_upgrade_Mercury_concentration_change.png&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effect of using B technology
&lt;img src=&#34;./image_for_personal_post/2ndupgrade_Mercury_concentration_change.jpg&#34; width=&#34;856&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-discussion-of-visualisation-method&#34;&gt;3. Discussion of visualisation method&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I mainly implemented the visualization scheme presented above. The aim is to compare the changes directly with the &amp;ldquo;same&amp;rdquo; color scale and unit in each graph. Since the original color scale was not clearly presented in the reference (see the first graph), I had to emulate the color scale as close as possible using R package. The advantage of using the same color scale is :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two graphs can be compared together directly. The numerical change is linearly mapped to color change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The consistency through out the project makes it easier to understand the changes in each scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disadvantages are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The color scale used here is not necessarily color blind friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although the numerical changes are mapped to color changes, sometimes its not strong enough to produce or spot a color change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your opinion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a view of full view of my work, visit my Github profile here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shirzartenwer/master_project_work_showcase&#34; title=&#34;Master Project Showcase&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to my Github Master Project link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
